<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on joh.fi</title>
    <link>https://joh.fi/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on joh.fi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 19:22:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joh.fi/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My first patch to GNOME</title>
      <link>https://joh.fi/blog/2012-12-16-my-first-patch-to-gnome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2012 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joh.fi/blog/2012-12-16-my-first-patch-to-gnome/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve used open source software for many years now but I haven&amp;rsquo;t really contributed back to any of the open source communities. I have filled some bug reports but other than that I&amp;rsquo;ve been simply a happy (and sometimes less happy) user. However yesterday I took the first step by doing tiny tiny contribution to GNOME or to be specific to gnome-session. The funny thing is that it was all because of selfish reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing binary heap without an array</title>
      <link>https://joh.fi/blog/2011-11-17-implementing-binary-heap-without-an-array/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2011 17:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joh.fi/blog/2011-11-17-implementing-binary-heap-without-an-array/</guid>
      <description>So I had this school assignment to implement a binary heap with a twist of not using an array to store the binary tree. You might think that this is an easy problem to solve and after some thinking it turns out that it isn&amp;rsquo;t much harder than the generic array implementation. However if this is the first time you&amp;rsquo;re implementing binary heap this way, you&amp;rsquo;ll likely find it difficult to insert new nodes in O(lg n) time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler</title>
      <link>https://joh.fi/blog/2011-09-27-project-euler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2011 14:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joh.fi/blog/2011-09-27-project-euler/</guid>
      <description>Project Euler is a website containing computational problems intended to be solved by small programs. Currently there are 351 problems to be solved and all of the problems should be doable within one- minute-rule. In other words you are doing something wrong if computing the solution takes more than one minute (or at least your program could be optimized). If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in programming or mathematics then Project Euler is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>