<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Encryption on joh.fi</title>
    <link>https://joh.fi/categories/encryption/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Encryption on joh.fi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 20:08:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://joh.fi/categories/encryption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Ubuntu 13.10 on top of encrypted lvm</title>
      <link>https://joh.fi/blog/2014-03-15-ubuntu-13.10-encrypted-lvm-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 20:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joh.fi/blog/2014-03-15-ubuntu-13.10-encrypted-lvm-installation/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ubuntu&amp;rsquo;s installer provides a simple option for installing on top of encrypted lvm. The option however does not allow to modify partition layout and that for me is a showstopper. The other option is to create an encrypted container for all the partitions which works fine but then one has to enter the passphrase to each and every device individually.
This guide explains how to install ubuntu on top of an encrypted lvm and also give user the power of specifying partition layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Encrypted Windows and Arch Linux dual-boot installation using UEFI</title>
      <link>https://joh.fi/blog/2016-03-05-encrypted-windows-and-arch-linux-dual-boot-installation-using-uefi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joh.fi/blog/2016-03-05-encrypted-windows-and-arch-linux-dual-boot-installation-using-uefi/</guid>
      <description>I will start this with a note that this is not a tutorial type of post. It&amp;rsquo;s just to remind myself how I did this myself. I&amp;rsquo;m way too lazy to keep updating tutorials and therefore it&amp;rsquo;s easier to just post some rough guidelines instead of step by step instructions.
For some time now I&amp;rsquo;ve been running a pretty nice dual boot setup with my trusty old Lenovo X220. I have a 512GB Samsung 840 Pro SSD divided between a Windows 10 and Arch Linux installations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>